WireMin Terms & Privacy Policy
==============================

WireMin is a democratized network based on interconnected users' devices. WireMin apps are designed as equal nodes in the network that communicate with other users on common protocols. It is not based on cloud service or central servers, so no single bit of user data will be transferred or stored in any computing facility controlled by us. WireMin messages and contents, as well as user identities and social relationships are stored and replicated among users' devices with end-to-end encryption, which only allows the users’ and the intended recipients’ access. Our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy are available below. 

**Terms of Service**

We don’t operate a service. So there is nothing regarding the service.

Instead, WireMin establishes a self-organizing network only by a number of active instances of WireMin apps. WireMin, as a protocol, utilizes advanced security and time-tested cryptography to provide a private messaging tool and social network. All of those are achieved in a democratized network without relying on a cloud service or back-end server.

**About Our App**

Minimum Age. 

By accessing our services, you confirm that you’re at least 13 years old and meet the minimum age of digital consent in your country.

Account Registration. 

To create an account, the only thing you need is the App. It can be done even without the internet. The associated identity and credentials will be stored only on your devices. No data will be collected.

Privacy of User Data.

No single bit of user data will be collected. WireMin is not even capable of doing that.

Please read our Privacy Policy to understand how we safeguard the information you share and store when using our apps. To establish the WireMin Network, you agree to our data practices including replication of your encrypted information and metadata to other users in different countries and the relay of encrypted data from other users. 

Software. 

To enable new features and enhanced functionality, you consent to [downloading and installing updates](https://wiremin.org/index.html#/#download) for our apps. 

Fees and Taxes. 

You are responsible for data and mobile carrier fees and taxes associated with the devices on which you use our apps. 

**Using WireMin**

Our Terms and Policies. 

You must use our apps according to our Terms and posted Policies. Although we don’t have such an ability to disable your account or prevent you from creating a new one, you might be blacklisted if the majority of users wish to.

Legal and Acceptable Use. 

You agree to use our apps only for legal, authorized, and acceptable purposes. You will not use (or assist others in using) our apps in ways that: 

(A) Violate or infringe the rights of WireMin, our users, or others, including privacy, publicity, intellectual property, or other proprietary rights; 

(B) Involve sending illegal or impermissible communications such as bulk messaging, auto-messaging, and auto-dialing. 

Harm to WireMin.

You must not (or assist others to) access, use, modify, distribute, transfer, or exploit our apps in unauthorized manners, or in ways that harm the WireMin Network. For example, you must not

(A) Gain or try to gain unauthorized access to our apps or devices of our users; 

(B) Disrupt with the integrity or performance of the network; 

(C) Create an overwhelming amount of messages or storage requests through unauthorized or automated means; 

(D) Collect information about our users in any unauthorized manners; 

(E) Sell, rent, or monetize our apps.

Keeping Your Account Secure.

WireMin offers strong privacy by design and does not have the ability to access your passcode, your messages, or your social relationships. You are responsible for keeping your device and your WireMin Account safe and secure. If you lose your phone or forget your passcode, follow the steps on our [FAQ page](https://wiremin.org/index.html#/FAQ). Unfortunately, we are not able to recover or reset your Account.

No Access to Emergency Services. 

Our apps do not provide access to emergency service providers like the police, fire department, hospitals, or other public safety organizations. Make sure you can contact emergency service providers through a mobile, fixed-line telephone, or other services.

Third-party Services. 

Our apps may allow you to access, use, or interact with third-party websites, apps, content, and other products and services. when you use third-party sites or services, you are using their services and not our services and they, not we, are responsible for their practices. You should read the applicable third-party privacy policies before using such third-party tools on our Site.

**Your Rights and License with WireMin**

Your Rights. 

You own/take the right to create accounts on WireMin, and send messages at any time. You have the right to have your encrypted messages or data relayed and stored by other users.

Other User’s Rights. 

Other users have the right to relay and store their encrypted messages and data on your device in an anonymous way. However, you cannot and will not be liable to the other users for any indirect, consequential, exemplary, incidental, or punitive damages, including lost profits, arising from relaying or storing others' messages and data 

WireMin’s Rights. 

We own all copyrights, trademarks, domains, logos, trade dress, trade secrets, patents, and other intellectual property rights associated with our apps. You may not use our copyrights, trademarks, domains, logos, trade dress, patents, and other intellectual property rights unless you have our written permission. Please contact us to report copyright, trademark, or other intellectual property infringement.

WireMin’s License to You.

WireMin grants you a limited, revocable, non-exclusive, and non-transferable license to use our apps in accordance with these Terms. 

**Disclaimers and Limitations**

Disclaimers. 

YOU USE OUR APPS AT YOUR OWN RISK AND ARE SUBJECT TO THE FOLLOWING DISCLAIMERS. WE PROVIDE OUR APPS ON AN “AS IS” BASIS WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, AND FREEDOM FROM COMPUTER VIRUS OR OTHER HARMFUL CODE. WIREMIN DOES NOT WARRANT THAT ANY INFORMATION PROVIDED BY US IS ACCURATE, COMPLETE, OR USEFUL, THAT OUR APPS WILL BE OPERATIONAL, ERROR-FREE, SECURE, OR SAFE, OR THAT OUR APPS WILL FUNCTION WITHOUT DISRUPTIONS, DELAYS, OR IMPERFECTIONS. WE DO NOT CONTROL, AND ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR, CONTROLLING HOW OR WHEN OUR USERS USE OUR APPS. WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE ACTIONS OR INFORMATION (INCLUDING CONTENT) OF OUR USERS OR OTHER THIRD PARTIES. YOU RELEASE US, AFFILIATES, DIRECTORS, OFFICERS, EMPLOYEES, PARTNERS, AND AGENTS (TOGETHER, “WIREMIN PARTIES”) FROM ANY CLAIM, COMPLAINT, CAUSE OF ACTION, CONTROVERSY, OR DISPUTE (TOGETHER, “CLAIM”) AND DAMAGES, KNOWN AND UNKNOWN, RELATING TO, ARISING OUT OF, OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH ANY SUCH CLAIM YOU HAVE AGAINST ANY THIRD PARTIES. 

Limitation of Liability. 

THE WIREMIN PARTIES WILL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ANY LOST PROFITS OR CONSEQUENTIAL, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INDIRECT, OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES RELATING TO, ARISING OUT OF, OR IN ANY WAY IN CONNECTION WITH OUR TERMS, US, OR OUR APPS, EVEN IF THE WIREMIN PARTIES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. OUR AGGREGATE LIABILITY RELATING TO, ARISING OUT OF, OR IN ANY WAY IN CONNECTION WITH OUR TERMS, US, OR OUR APPS WILL NOT EXCEED ONE HUNDRED DOLLARS ($100). THE FOREGOING DISCLAIMER OF CERTAIN DAMAGES AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY WILL APPLY TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW. THE LAWS OF SOME STATES OR JURISDICTIONS MAY NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF CERTAIN DAMAGES, SO SOME OR ALL OF THE EXCLUSIONS AND LIMITATIONS SET FORTH ABOVE MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU. NOTWITHSTANDING ANYTHING TO THE CONTRARY IN OUR TERMS, IN SUCH CASES, THE LIABILITY OF THE WIREMIN PARTIES WILL BE LIMITED TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW. 

Availability of Our Apps. 

Our apps or the network may be interrupted, due to maintenance, upgrades, or network or equipment failures. We may discontinue some or all of our apps, including certain features and the support for specific devices and platforms, at any time. 

**Resolving Disputes and Ending Terms**

Resolving Disputes. 

You agree to resolve any Claim you have with us relating to or arising out of our Terms, us, or our apps exclusively in the country or state we selected. You also agree to submit to the personal jurisdiction of such courts for the purpose of litigating all such disputes.

Ending these Terms. 

You may end these Terms with WireMin at any time by deleting the WireMin App from your device. We reserve the right to modify, suspend, or terminate your access to or use of our apps anytime for any reason, such as if you violate the letter or spirit of our Terms or create harm, risk, or possible legal exposure for WireMin. Although we don’t have the ability to enforce that for now. The following provisions will survive termination of your relationship with WireMin: “Licenses,” “Disclaimers,” “Limitation of Liability,” “Resolving dispute,” “Availability” and “Ending these Terms,” and “General”.

**General**

WireMin may update the Terms from time to time. When we update our Terms, we will update the “Last Modified” date associated with the updated Terms. Your continued use of our apps confirms your acceptance of our updated Terms and supersedes any prior Terms. You will comply with all applicable export control and trade sanctions laws. Our Terms cover the entire agreement between you and WireMin regarding our apps. If you do not agree with our Terms, you should stop using our apps.

If we fail to enforce any of our Terms, that does not mean we waive the right to enforce them. If any provision of the Terms is deemed unlawful, void, or unenforceable, that provision shall be deemed severable from our Terms and shall not affect the enforceability of the remaining provisions. Our apps are not intended for distribution to or use in any country where such distribution or use would violate local law or would subject us to any regulations in another country. We reserve the right to limit our apps in any country. If you have specific questions about these Terms, please contact us. 

* * *

**Privacy Policy**

WireMin utilizes state-of-the-art cryptography and end-to-end encryption to provide tools for private messaging and social networking activities to users worldwide (“Apps”). Your identity, messages, and social relationship data are always end-to-end encrypted so that they can never be shared or viewed by anyone except for you and the intended recipients.

**Information You Provide**

No user information will be provided to us, not a single bit. There is information you provided that is stored in your own device and replicated on other users' devices, in a way that is anonymous and end-to-end encrypted without revealing the content and the identity of the owner.

Account Information. 

A root secret is created when you create an account, which is only stored on your devices. It is the only information used to control an account fully. We support mnemonic backup in case of forgetting a passcode or losing the device. But it is on your own to keep it in a safe and secret place. You may optionally add other information to your accounts, such as a profile name and avatar. This information is end-to-end encrypted, shared with intended recipients, and may be replicated in other users' devices anonymously

Messages.

WireMin and unintended users cannot decrypt or otherwise access the content of your messages or profile data. Messages will be temporarily relayed and stored by others' devices for hours. While only your and intended recipients can decrypt messages. Message history is kept only on you and your recipients' devices.

No user information is stored in any computing facility controlled by us or any server. WireMin apps can deliver messages without user identities and their social relationships.

Phone Contacts.

WireMin doesn't read phone contacts or your phone number for account registration or recommending connections/contacts to you. 

User Support. 

If you contact WireMin User Support, any personal data you may share with us is kept only for the purposes of researching the issue and contacting you about your case. 

Device Information.

WireMin collects minimum device information, such as version number, platform, etc. All of this information is sent without association with the user account. WireMin App doesn't read or transfer the precise geo-location like GPS coordinates. Occasionally for WireMin App on mobile devices, an additional device notification token (e.g. iOS devices) may be collected, to enable push notifications. Again, that information is collected without exposing user identity or the device's IP which eliminates the possibility of user tracking.

Diagnostics Information.

WireMin may optionally collect information to diagnose crashes and malfunctions of the apps. All of the information has no association with the user account or user identity. Collecting that information may expose your device's IP depending on third-party debugging service providers. WireMin allows opt-out of such collections.

**Information We May Share**

We don't have user information of any sort, so nothing will be shared. 

Third Parties.

WireMin leverages third parties to achieve a better user experience and improve the stability of the App.

• We employed Apple Push Service and Google Push Service for messaging notifications when the WireMin is not running. Both services require platform-specific device identifiers to be sent to these third parties, which can be turned off by disabling Push Notification.

• We optionally collect crash point information based on third-party services (Firebase for the mobile platform and Sentry for the desktop platform). It can be turned off by navigating to Personal > Privacy and Security > Allow Sending Diagnostics.

WireMin restrictedly sends data to these third parties. All data is anonymous and does not contain any information related to your account or message content.

External Websites. 

You may open a URL, which leads you to a third-party website that is displayed in WireMin apps. Their Terms and Privacy Policies govern your use of those services.

Other Instances where WireMin may Need to Share

• To meet applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request.

• To enforce applicable Terms, including investigation of potential violations.

• To detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues.

• To protect against harm to the rights, property, or safety of WireMin, our users, or the public as required or permitted by law.

**Updates**

We will update this Privacy Policy as needed so that it is updated, accurate, and as clear as possible. Your continued use of our apps confirms your acceptance of our updated Privacy Policy. 

**Terms**

Please also read our Terms which also govern the Terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://wiremin.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Effective as of Feb 15, 2021

Updated July 20, 2022
